

Sacramento, California

# **Summary** \_

I've always been extremely interested in computer security, as well as general information security, and privacy.

My professional background has been in software engineering and Linux server administration. I have 10+ years experience deploying and administering Linux servers, both physically and in a cloud environment. Primarily my software development experience has been in PHP, MySQL, HTML/CSS, and JavaScript, as well as various frameworks built upon those technologies. I also have practical experience in C, Python, C#, and Java.

I'd like to transition into a security focused role, rather than a development focused role, moving forward with my career. I believe my years of experience as a developer and systems administrator have given me practical insight into what can go wrong when securing an environment, both technically and non-technically.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

### **Capitol Compliance Management**

Sacramento, California

Aug. 2014 - Jul. 2015

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2015 - PRESENT

- Cloud deployment and administration of Linux servers (Ubuntu via Digital Ocean).
- Backend web development in PHP and Python.
- · MySQL database management.
- · Website reliability and malware removal.

#### **Prestwood I.T. Solutions** Citrus Heights, California

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

• Back End Development in PHP, MySQL, VB, C#, and MSSQL.

- Front End Development in HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript (¡Query, VueJS).
- Authored Standard Operating Procedures for Web Division.
- · Technical Lead of Web Division.
- · Served on Prestwood's Board of Directors.

orcuttbay.com Santa Maria, California

FREELANCE CONSULTANT May. 2009 - Jan. 2014

- Full Stack Web development utilizing Code Igniter Framework and WordPress CMS.
- · Ubuntu Linux Apache2 server administration for multiple clients in shared environment, hosted onsite.
- · Organic SEO campaigns with Google Analytics and Webmasters toolkits.

# **30th Space Wing Public Affairs**

Vandenberg Air Force Base, California

STUDENT INTERN (GS3) Oct. 2008 - Sept. 2011

- Maintained and expanded 30th Space Wing Intranet site for Public Affairs.
- Developed and maintained Java Applet for emergency exercise communication.
- Acted as first point of contact between Vandenberg Air Force Base and the general public.

# El Dorado Broadcasting (formerly Clear Channel Radio)

Santa Maria, California

Oct. 2006 - July. 2008

Developed and maintained PHP/MySQL sites for all radio stations under El Dorado Broadcasters in Santa Maria market.

# Education\_

#### **California State University Sacramento**

Sacramento, California

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

Jan. 2016 - Dec. 2019

• Certificate of Cyber Defense and Operations.

## Santa Maria, California

ASSOSIATE OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Allan Hancock College

Aug. 2007 - Jun. 2011

RYAN E. KOZAK · RÉSUMÉ **FEBRUARY 8, 2019**